{"tossups": [{}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man came to power after his brother was assassinated at Corfe Castle. This man lost control of the coastline after Byrhtnoth was defeated at the Battle of Maldon, and his son lost control of this man\u2019s kingdom to Canute after the Battle of Assandun. This man\u2019s territories were invaded by Sweyn Forkbeard after this man ordered the St. Brices Day Massacre in an attempt to stop paying the Danegeld tribute. For ten points, name this father of Edmund Ironside whose nickname incorrectly suggests that he was not well prepared.", "answer": "<b> Aethelred</b> the Unready (or<b> Aethelred</b> II)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In one episode of this TV show, copies of Ruth Benedict\u2019s<em> The Chrysanthemum and the Sword</em> are handed out before a visit by Japanese executives. In another episode, Margaret, the daughter of Roger Sterling, has her wedding interrupted by John F. Kennedy\u2019s assassination; that event also cements Betty\u2019s decision to divorce her philandering husband. Lucky Strike is a major client of the protagonists of, for ten points, what AMC show about Don Draper, a 1960s advertising executive?", "answer": "<b> Mad Men</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "A city in this country was given to the English king Charles II as dowry in 1661; that colony in this country was evacuated just 23 years later. A succession crisis began when the Portuguese king Sebastian I died in a battle in this country. An army from this modern-day country defeated a Southern neighbor at the Battle of Tondibi, and this country declared independence under a king of its Alaouite Dynasty, which succeeded the Saadi dynasty of King Ahmad al-Mansur. For ten points, name this country whose kings often ruled from the city of Marrakech.", "answer": "<b> Morocco</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "2 million dollar land acquisition. For ten points, name this Secretary of State under Andrew Johnson whose namesake \u201cFolly\u201d resulted in America\u2019s purchase of Alaska.", "answer": "William<b> Seward</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The oldest continually operating venue of this type is thought to be in College Park, Maryland, where it was opened by the United States Army Signal Corps. One of these locations was built in an area then known as Orchard Place, where Douglas set up manufacturing facilities during World War II. In 1958, Pete Quesada suggested that Dwight Eisenhower should name a newly opened one of these facilities in Washington D.C. after his secretary of state. A naval flying ace named Butch O\u2019Hare inspired the name of, for ten points, what type of transportation facility?", "answer": "<b> airport</b>s", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Description acceptable. Twenty-six people of this type were put to death after the San Felipe incident in 1596. James Hepburn worked primarily with this specific group of people, whose persecution is the subject of the novel<em> Silence</em>. These people were often forced to trample on images known as<em> fumi-e</em> to repudiate their faith. Francis Xavier was instrumental in first reaching this group of people, who were primarily converted by the Portuguese. For ten points, name this persecuted class of individuals who were converted in towns like Nagasaki.", "answer": "<b> Japan</b>ese<b> Christians</b> (prompt on partial answer)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "The forces of Mindarus were routed by this city at the Battle of Cyzicus [sizz-ih-kus]. After a storm prevented this city\u2019s ships from rescuing drowning sailors, this city sentenced six of its generals to death. A subset of this city\u2019s fleet led by Conon was relieved after this city won the Battle of Arginusae; that victory gave this city the false confidence to ignore a peace offering from Lysander, after which their fleet was utterly destroyed in a 405 BC battle. For ten points, name this city that was ruled by the Thirty Tyrants after Sparta defeated them to win the Peloponnesian War.", "answer": "<b> Athens</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This feature stretches from its namesake city to Palpa via the Pampas de Jumana. In January 2018, a 40-year-old truck driver was arrested for driving through and damaging part of this UNESCO World Heritage Site. One theory claims that the constellation Orion is anamorphically represented by the giant spider in this series. A hummingbird and a condor are among the other curvilinear geoglyphs in, for ten points, what series of earthworks created by a namesake ancient Peruvian people?", "answer": "<b> Nazca Lines</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "This country\u2019s elite were nicknamed the Wabenzi for their love of Mercedes-Benz cars. This country perpetrated the Garissa and Wagalla massacres against an ethnic group that it had fought in the Shifta War. Ethnic tension in this country increased after Raila Odinga claimed fraud in his electoral loss to Mwai Kibaki. This country\u2019s Kalenjin people gained power when Daniel Arap Moi assumed the presidency as head of the KANU party. For ten points, name this African country whose first President was Jomo Kenyatta.", "answer": "<b> Kenya</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This party\u2019s recent presidential candidates have included Ted Weill, Andre Barnett, and Rocky de la Fuente, none of whom got more than half a percent of the vote. Former Democratic Governor of Colorado Richard Lamm ran for this party\u2019s Presidential ticket in 1996. This party, whose platform includes the Balanced Budget Amendment, Congressional term limits, and opposition to NAFTA, was founded by a man who built Electronic Data Systems. For ten points, name this political party founded by Ross Perot.", "answer": "<b> Reform</b> Party of the United States of America (do not accept \u201cAmerican Reform Party\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In 1917, this figure traveled to Bloomington and delivered a speech at the Eagle\u2019s Hall encouraging a power shutdown. This figure was arrested and sentenced to 20 years in prison during the Paint Creek War. This woman organized a march from Pennsylvania to Theodore Roosevelt\u2019s hometown of Oyster Bay to protest the lax enforcement of child labor laws among mill owners. A progressive magazine founded in the 1970s was named after, for ten points, what \u201cmost dangerous woman in America\u201d who agitated strikes for the United Mine Workers?", "answer": "Mary Harris<b> Jones</b> (accept Mother<b> Jones</b>) BONUS:<em> Mother Jones</em> magazine employed this activist and filmmaker as an editor in the 1980s. His works include<em> Sicko</em> and<em> Fahrenheit 9/11</em>. ANSWER: Michael<b> Moore</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This scientist sent Humphry Davy a 300-page book of notes he had taken at his lectures, which led to Davy hiring this man as an assistant after he damaged his eyesight. This man, who performed the \u201cice pail\u201d experiment and discovered benzene, had his work given a mathematical treatment by James Clark Maxwell. Electric and magnetic fields were discovered by, for ten points, what British scientist who names the law of induction and a type of \u201ccage?\u201d", "answer": "Michael<b> Faraday</b>", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Christian II lost control of this country after it seceded from the Kalmar Union. For ten points, named this country ruled by the Vasa Dynasty in Scandinavia.", "answer": "<b> Pasargadae</b> ([pass-ar-gah-die], but be lenient) <b></b> (1) <b>In a fit of insanity, a ruler from this country murdered multiple members of the</b> <b>Sture family. The Petri brothers helped implement the Protestant Reformation in this country, which received (+) Estonia as a vassal state after the Livonian War, and occupied</b> <b>Poland-Lithuania during the Deluge. A queen of this country converted to (*)</b> Catholicism shortly after abdicating the throne at age 28. Christian II lost control of this country after it seceded from the Kalmar Union. For ten points, named this country ruled by the Vasa Dynasty in Scandinavia. ANSWER:<b> Sweden</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Robert Stockwell and Donka Minkova wrote a work asking if the changes that resulted in this event could be packaged. The term for this event was coined by a Danish scholar</b> <b>named Otto Jespersen. One theory claims that the nobility\u2019s declining use of (+)</b> <b>French</b> <b>in favor of English brought about this event, while other historians claim that it resulted from the mixing of accents after the Black Death forced populations to move to southeast England. Prior to this event, (*) </b> words in Middle English like \u201cmice\u201d were pronounced as \u201cmees.\u201dFor ten points, name this linguistic event in which the pronunciation in a certain type of sound changed.", "answer": "<b> Great Vowel Shift</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Linguistics"}, {"question": "<b>In a text written after the death of his father-in-law, this author described the customs the ancient Britons. This author of</b><em><b> Agricola</b></em><b> described Sejanus\u2019 manipulation of an emperor in another work. This author\u2019s account of the reign of (+) Caligula is a lost section of a text that describes the assassination attempt on Agrippina and begins just after the death of Augustus. This author wrote about the reigns of the emperors (*)</b> Tiberius, Claudius and Nero in his most famous work. For ten points, name this Roman writer of a history of the Flavian emperors and the<em> Annals</em>.", "answer": "Publius Cornelius<b> Tacitus</b> Page 11", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>During a siege of this city, National Guard troops bivouacked in a partially-built opera house designed by Charles Garnier. A composer who worked in this city wrote a</b><em><b> Treatise </b><b>on Harmony</b></em><b> and the opera</b><em><b> Castor and Pollux</b></em><b>, and was contrasted with Giovanni (+) Pergolesi in the \u201cQuarrel of the Buffoons.\u201d This city was home to an opera company led by a man who died of (*) </b> gangrene after hitting his foot with a baton. For ten points, for what city\u2019s opera company did Jean-Philippe Rameau and Jean-Baptiste Lully write on behalf of Louis XIV?", "answer": "<b> Paris</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Opera"}, {"question": "<b>In this novel, a widow symbolically discards her sewing machine into a cement tank full of water in her yard. This book\u2019s fifth and final chapter, which was appended forty years</b> <b>after the previous sections, tells of how (+)</b> <b>Father Kleinsorge dies from complications of</b> <b>Father Kleinsorge dies from complications of</b> <b>falling on ice. This book follows the lives of six people as they deal with (*)</b> <b>falling on ice. This book follows the lives of six people as they deal with (*)</b> mysterious red lesions on their skin in the aftermath of a devastating attack on August 6, 1945. For ten points, name this John Hersey book titled after a Japanese city that was hit by an atomic bomb.", "answer": "<b> Hiroshima</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In this state, Robert Hill organized tenant farmers and sharecroppers at a church near Hoop Spur; after a white man was shot trying to interrupt that meeting, one of the largest race riots in American history broke out. Walter F. White was sent to investigate that riot in this state\u2019s town of (+) Elaine. The Supreme Court case</b><em><b> Cooper v. Aaron</b></em><b> arose from this state\u2019s refusal to enforce another Supreme Court decision. After this state\u2019s National Guard was deployed by governor (*) </b> Orval Faubus, Dwight Eisenhower federalized it and sent the 101st Airborne Division to Central High School. For ten points, name this state where school desegregation began with the Little Rock Nine.", "answer": "<b> Arkansas</b> ", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This body was reduced in number by Thomas Grey and Hardress Waller after it tried negotiating with the Treaty of Newport. Members of this body could not serve as (+) military commanders by the Self-Denying Ordinance. This body was changed</b> <b>from a \u201cLong\u201d version to a \u201cRump\u201d version after it was (*)</b> purged by Thomas Pride. During the English Civil War, the Roundheads fought as a side named for this body against King Charles I. The House of Commons and the House of Lords form, for ten points, what legislative body in England?", "answer": "English<b> Parliament</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}